（ゼツ）ぐわぁ！
（サクラ）それにしても
どうやって→
ネジさんのチャクラのまま
変化できたの？
Tell me. How were you able to
recreate Neji's chakra?!
アンタ　吸い取った相手のチャクラを
そのまま利用して→
You are able to manipulate
the chakra that you absorb…
同じチャクラに変化できるのね？
そうでしょ？
You can transform your chakra
into your victim!
《シノ：今は大戦の真っ只中。
Isn't that right?!
そんなとき味方の部隊に
白いヤツが紛れ込んだ。
As war rages on…
The White Zetsu infiltrate
the Allied Forces.
部隊の周囲には結界があり
簡単には侵入できない。
A barrier protects the camp surroundings,
making infiltration difficult.
だが　どうやら
結界の漏れがあるらしい。
But it seems there might be
an opening in the barrier.
俺たち八班は
そこを探りに来たのだが》
Team 8 has come to
investigate this.
（キバ）おいおい　これって俺たち→
I think we might have just walked
into something dangerous.
やばいとこに入り込んじまったん
じゃねえのか？
（シノ）だが　これではっきりした。
Well, at least it's clear now.
ここが結界の漏れている場所だ
ここからヤツらは潜り込んだ。
This is the spot
where the barrier is open.
This is where they're entering from.
（ヒナタ）けっこうな数がいるみたい
気をつけてね。
There are quite a few of them.
Please be careful!
白眼！
Byakugan!
キバ君！
（キバ）牙通牙！
Kiba!
Fang Over Fang!
（ゼツ）ぐわっ！
秘術　蟲玉！
Hidden Jutsu: Beetle Sphere!
シノ君！
Shino!
いったい何体いるんだよ？
How many of 'em are there?!
（シノ）ヤツらに迂闊に触れるな。
Don’t let them touch you.
If we do,
they’ll absorb our chakra!
なぜなら
俺たちのチャクラを吸収する。
Easier said than done!
んなこと言ったって　触らなくて
どうやって倒すんだ！？
How are we going to take them down
without touching them?
I just sent out a messenger owl.
（ヒナタ）
さっき　連絡ミミズクを飛ばしたの。
The Sealing Corps should arrive
shortly to seal up this mine.
もうすぐ封印班が来て
この炭坑を封印してくれるはず。
So we just have to wait until then?
（キバ）それまで
もちこたえるしかねえのか。
Damn it! Things are only getting worse!
クソ　このままじゃジリ貧だぜ。
Hinata! Kiba! Shino!
ヒナタさん　キバさん　シノさん！
They're here!
来た。
封印班か。
Are you the Sealing Corps?
We'll seal this immediately!
すぐに　ここを封印します。
こちらから出てください！
Please exit this way!
We're not going to let you go!
逃がすか！
They're persistent!
しつこいんだよ　通牙！
Fang Over Fang!
What?! There's oil on the ground?
なに？　地面の油に。
（赤丸）ワンワン！
Paper Bombs used for mining?!
This isn't good!
It's going to explode!
採掘に使う起爆札。
Akamaru, time for Dynamic Marking!
まずい　爆発するぞ。
赤丸　ダイナミックマーキングだ！
ワンワン！
キャン！
White Zetsu's Trap
ゲホッ　ゲホッ！　大丈夫か？　赤丸。
ク～ン。
Are you all right, Akamaru?!
ひでぇなこりゃ。
This is awful…
誰かいるか？　シノ！　ヒナタ！
Is anyone there?!
Shino! Hinata!
（シノ）俺なら　ここにいる。
I'm over here.
シノ　無事だったのか！
ああ。
Shino… You're okay!
ヒナタは？
わからない。
Yeah.
Where's Hinata?
I don't know.
まさか　あんなところに
起爆札があったなんて…。
Those Paper Bombs were a surprise.
チッ！　とにかく　ヒナタを捜そうぜ。
We'd better find Hinata.
キバ　お前の鼻で捜せないのか？
Can you locate her
with your scent?
ダメだ。　煙のにおいがひどくて。
I can't…
The smell of smoke is too strong.
ヒナタ！　ヒナタ！
Hinata!
どうやら　敵の気配はねえ。
I don't sense the enemy anymore.
白いヤツらは
みんな吹き飛んだみたいだな。
I guess those white guys
were blown away.
Call it fortune in misfortune.
不幸中の幸いだぜ。
But with a blast that strong,
the exit might've been sealed off.
それにしても　こうぶっ壊れちゃ
出口も塞がってんじゃねえのか？
うん？　キバ！
Kiba!
Hey!
おい！
Nope… He's dead.
ダメだ…　死んでる。
Who's there?!
誰だ？
Kiba! Shino!
キバ君！　シノ君！
Hinata, you're all right!
ヒナタ！　無事だったか！
ワン！　ワン！
The ground gave way and
I fell to the lower level.
床が崩れて
下の階に落ちちゃって。
That's…
それって…。
It's unfortunate…
かわいそうなことをしちまった。
Wasn't there one more
from the Sealing Corps?
確か　封印班は　もう一人いたな。
早く捜してやらねえと。
Let's look for him.
Yes. Let's find him and
get out of here.
そうだね。　早く見つけて
脱出しましょう。
（シノ）ああ。
Yeah…
We can't escape.
Huh? Why?!
脱出はできない。
The explosion didn't kill this shinobi.
あん？　なんでだよ？
彼の死因は
爆発によるものではない。
He was fatally wounded
by a kunai.
致命傷となったのは
クナイによる刺し傷だ。
Then he was killed
after the explosion?!
それじゃ　コイツは爆発のあとに
殺されたってのか？
Yes… The enemy survived.
そうだ。
まだ　ヤツの生き残りがいる。
They can absorb a victim's chakra,
but also take that victim's form.
ヤツは　吸い取ったチャクラの持ち主に
変化することができる。
If I were him, I could take advantage
of the confusion,
俺が　ヤツなら　このどさくさに紛れ
再び　部隊に潜入することを企む。
and slip right back into our forces.
So you're saying
there's a fake among us?
It's not impossible.
この中に　ニセモノがいるってのか？
Hey, hey!
We're on the same team!
その可能性がないわけではない。
We'd be able to
see through a fake, right?
おいおい！　俺たち同じ班だ。
ニセモノがいたら気づくだろう。
I wonder about that…
Hinata, why aren't you using
your Byakugan?
そうだろうか？
Well, because…
ヒナタ　なぜ　白眼を使わない？
the Sealing Team's barrier jutsu
was incomplete when it was activated…
それは　封印班の結界術が
半端に発動してて…。
and disrupted my Byakugan.
Is that the truth?
それで　白眼が乱れちゃって…。
Hey, you suspect Hinata?!
それは　本当か？
Kiba, are you telling the truth
that your nose isn't working?
お前　ヒナタを疑うのかよ？
Not me too?!
キバ　鼻が効かないというのは
本当なのか？
What about you?
Are you the real Shino?!
俺まで疑うのか？
They didn't touch me
in our earlier skirmish.
そういう　テメエこそ
本物なんだろうな？
But any amount of chakra can be
sucked out through your insects!
俺は　さっきの戦いで
ヤツには触れていない。
Well, there's no way
I can disprove that…
けど　蟲からお前のチャクラは
いくらでも吸い取れんだろ。
However, I am the real me.
そうであれば
証明する手立てはない。
And I'm the real me!
So am I.
だが俺はホンモノだ。
This is a futile argument.
俺だってホンモノだぜ。
That's because none of us can
prove that we are truly ourselves.
わ　私もです。
無意味な論争だ。
I know!
なぜなら　誰も自分が
ホンモノであることを立証できない。
If we can't trust each other,
let's go our own way!
I'll find the remaining one
on my own!
わかったよ。
そんなに信用できねえなら
別行動にしようぜ。
Let's go, Akamaru!
Kiba!
俺は勝手に残りの１人を捜す。
行くぞ　赤丸。
キバ君！
どうやら俺たちも→
互いに信じ合っていないようだな。
It seems we don't trust
each other either…
うぅ…。
助かった。
手を貸してくれないか？
Thank goodness!
Can you give me a hand?
え？　ギャーッ！
どうした？
What happened?!
第２の犠牲者が出ちまった。
ひどい…。
The second victim…
How terrible…
やはり　この中にニセモノがいる。
There is a fake among us, after all.
何の真似だ？
とぼけるなよ。
What's the big idea?!
Don't pretend!
The victim was holding this!
殺されたアイツは
これを握りしめていた。
From the scent,
it's a piece ripped from your clothes!
このニオイは　お前の服の切れ端だぜ。
Shino! You're the fake!
シノ　お前がニセモノだな？
チッ！
You suddenly started talking
about fakes and what not.
急にニセモノだとか言い出して→
I had my doubts about you
from the start!
最初から　どうもおかしいと
思ったんだよ。
That piece got ripped off
in the explosion.
切れ端は　さっきの爆発で
吹き飛んだものだ。
And besides,
if I were the fake,
それに　もし　俺がニセモノなら→
why would I even bring it up?
どうして　わざわざ　そんなことを
言い出す必要がある？
You probably figured
if you bring it up first,
最初に言い出せば　いちばん
疑われねえとでも思ったんだろ？
no one would suspect you!
But, damn it, I wouldn't fall
for something like that!
だがあいにく　そんなことで
騙される俺じゃねえぜ！
Get ready!
覚悟しな！
Hold it, Kiba! Hinata!
待て　キバ　ヒナタ！
If we let the fake one
manipulate us,
we'll end up killing each other!
ニセモノにおどらされれば
同士討ちになる。
That's exactly what they want!
ヤツは　それを狙っている。
We're just playing
into their hands!
そうなれば思う壺だ！
♪～
《この状況で
一つだけ確定したことがある。
ニセモノは１人。
There's one thing I know
for sure in this situation.
なぜなら　２人ともニセモノなら
ここは躊躇なく俺を襲うはず。
Just one of us is the fake.
That's because if
they were both fake,
つまりヤツは　俺ともう１人の本物が
潰し合うのを待っている》
they would attack me
without hesitation.
In other words, whoever it is,
they're waiting for me and
the other real one to destroy each other.
どうするんだよ！
ずっとこのままでいる気か？
Then what do you intend to do?!
一つだけ　いい方法がある。
ジャンケンだ。
Stay here like this until
who knows when?
I just have one good idea.
は？
ジャンケンって　グー　チョキ　パーの？
Rock-Paper-Scissors.
Huh?!
Are you serious?
Rock-Paper-Scissors?
そうだ。　それで負けた者が
みんなの質問に答える。
Yes.
The loser must answer
every question the other two poses.
それって　順番に答えれば
いいんじゃねえのか？
Why can't we just take
turns answering?
ダメだ　ジャンケンだ。
Nope, Rock-Paper-Scissors.
なんで　こんなところで
ジャンケンなんだ？
I don't get why we're doing
Rock-Paper-Scissors here.
（３人）ジャンケンポン！
– Rock-Paper-Scissors!
勝った。
I won…
（２人）ジャンケンポン。
– Rock-Paper-Scissors!
チッ…。
お前の好きなものは？
What are your favorite things?
ビーフジャーキー。　そして赤丸との散歩だ。
Beef jerky and
walking with Akamaru.
ワンワン！
いいだろう　次。
Fine. Next.
ジャンケンポン。
Rock-Paper-Scissors!
あいこで　しょ。
ジャンケン…。
なあ　これジャンケンいらなくねえか？
Rock-Paper…
Say, do we have to do
the Paper-Scissors-Rock part?
いいや
これがいちばん重要なんだ。
This is the most important part.
ジャンケンポン。
Rock-Paper-Scissors.
あ…　私の負け。
I-I lose…
お前の好きなものは？
What are your favorite things?
I like…sweet things.
私の好きなものは　甘いもの。
あ？　ウソだろ？
Huh? That's a lie.
What? What's wrong?
何？　何が違うの？
C'mon, what you like
is Naruto, right?
だって　お前が好きなのは
ナルトだろ？
えっ　ええ…
これって　そんな質問コーナーなの？
A-Are these the type of
questions we're asking?!
ハハハッ　ウソだよ　ウソ！
Kidding! Just kidding!
次にいくぞ。
Next.
I was just joking.
なんだよ　冗談の通じないヤツだな。
Never mind, let's continue.
いいから次だ。
ヘイヘイ。
Okay, okay.
Rock-Paper-Scissors!
ジャンケンポン。
あいこで　しょ。
おめえの負けだ。
じゃあ聞くぜ。
You lost. So here's my question.
Only the real Shino would
know the answer!
これは　本物のシノにしか
答えられねえ質問だ。
When we went after Sasuke,
サスケ奪還のとき
お前だけ仲間はずれで→
you were the only one
left behind.
How did you feel about that?
本当は　どう思ってた？
I cannot answer that question.
その質問には答えられない。
In fact, I don't want to answer.
No fair!
いや　答えたくない。
If you play like that,
this whole thing is pointless!
そんなのアリかよ！
そんなこと言ったら
これやってる意味ねえだろうが。
If you want to know the truth,
take me down.
真実を知りたければ
俺を倒すんだな。
What?
There's meaning in this…
なんだと！
Rock-Paper-Scissors!
それに意味はある　ジャンケンの。
ジャンケンポン。
I won again!
ポン！
One more time…
What's the point of
saying it out loud like this?
また勝った。
ジャンケン…。
This is the most crucial part.
絶対　ジャンケンいらねえだろ。
これがいちばん重要なのだ。
Rock-Paper-Scissors!
It's your turn, Shino.
ジャンケンポン。
The game's over.
シノ君の番だよ。
Huh?! Who are you to
make the rules?!
この勝負は　ここまでだ。
I've been thinking…
は？　なにお前
勝手なこと言ってるんだ！
With Captain Yamato
held captive,
it's not unusual for them to
obtain personal intel about us.
考えてみれば
ヤマト隊長が捕らわれている以上→
They went as far as getting
personal data on us?!
ヤツらが俺たちの個人情報を
聞き出している可能性が高い。
Of course.
俺たちの個人情報なんてことまで
聞くか？
That's because part of their strategy
is to impersonate one of us.
聞くだろう。　なぜなら→
Because of that,
ヤツらは俺たちの誰かに
化けることを作戦としていた。
the thoughts and habits of
each person are crucial.
なら　一人ひとりの趣向や
癖にいたる情報は重要となる。
Sure, if you put it that way.
So everything we've been
doing is meaningless?
そういわれりゃ　そうだけど。
Don't make me keep
repeating myself.
それじゃ　今までのこと全部
無意味じゃねえかよ。
Doing Rock-Paper-Scissors
has a purpose.
何度も言わせるな。
ジャンケンをしたことに意味がある。
I don't trust both of you, after all.
I'm bringing both of you down!
俺は　やはり
お前たちを信じられない。
Shino!
Whose side are you on?!
２人とも倒させてもらう！
Damn it!
シノ！　テメエ　何しやがる。
Fine, I'll fight you!
Let's do it, Akamaru!
クソッ　こうなりゃ相手してやる。
Fang Over Fang!
いくぞ　赤丸！
ワンワン。
Kiba! I'll assist!
おりゃあ　牙通牙！
I'm sure he's the fake!
I won't let you get away!
With these flames,
you can't use your insects!
Get ready!
Take this…Fang Over Fang!
Ki…ba…
We did it!
キバ君　私も手を貸します。
Now we can escape.
きっと　彼がニセモノ。
That's true…just me.
はっ！
はぁ～！！
What?!
Akamaru?!
逃がしません！
Ta-da!
The star of the show appears!
この炎なら　蟲も使えない。
So you're the fake!
I was so nervous that you'd start
asking touchy questions.
覚悟しな　くらえ　牙通牙！
ワンワン！
Like he said,
the things we got out of Yamato,
about you, were really helpful.
ぐわぁ！
As a result,
キバ…。
you guys had a falling out
and saved me a lot of trouble.
Without your mutt,
even I can beat you.
やったぜ　これで脱出できる。
ワンワン！
So the Shino I fought was real.
そうね。
I'm so stupid!
私　一人が。
なに！？
You're right.
That's because
you're really stupid.
はぁ！！
あっ　赤丸！
You finally showed your true colors.
Huh? You're alive? How?
ジャジャーン！　真打ち登場。
Because of you,
お前が　ニセモノだったのか。
I had to sacrifice so
many of my precious insects.
変なことを聞かれはじめたときは
どうなるかと思ったけど→
Insects…
Then the one I defeated earlier
was an Insect Clone?!
ヤツの言っていたとおり→
Exactly.
ヤマトから聞きだした
お前たちのことが役に立ったね。
How did you know that
I was the fake?!
I didn't know which one
was fake.
おかげで　まんまと
仲間割れしてくれちゃって→
助かっちゃった。
It was on my mind,
犬っころのいないお前なら
僕でも勝てるね。
from the time the three of us
faced each other.
それじゃあ　俺は本物のシノを…。
Even if there was
a fake among us,
なんて　バカなんだ！
if it was possible
to stay transformed,
（シノ）そのとおりだ。
could we really fight in earnest?
なぜなら
本当にお前は　バカだからだ。
やっと　正体を現したな。
Gentle Fist!
Gotcha!
あれ！？　生きてたの？
どうして…。
お前のおかげで
大事な蟲たちを→
If we trust a comrade,
can we really allow ourselves
to bring down that person?
犠牲にしなければ
ならなくなったが…。
Then I started thinking about
something even more ridiculous.
蟲？　それじゃあ
さっき倒したのは蟲分身か。
そういうことだ。
If I'm going to be defeated
by someone like that,
どうして　僕がニセモノだって
わかったんだ？
then maybe it was for the best.
And then, it became clear.
どっちが　ニセモノか
わかっていたわけじゃない。
I'll have me, the real me,
get taken down.
俺たちが　最初に３人で
向かい合ったときから→
Then it would be guaranteed that
you would reveal yourself.
ずっと心の中で思っていた。
That's what
the Rock-Paper-Scissors was for.
３人の中に
ニセモノがいたとしても→
Rock-Paper-Scissors?
その姿で居続けられたら→
Those were hand signals.
本気で
戦うことなどできるのかと。
What's the point of saying it
out loud like this?
((うおっ！
This is the most crucial part.
After he said that,
I started to figure it out.
柔拳！
ぐわっ！
とどめだ！
(ぐわぁ！！))
Back then, the message
you gave me was…
"Follow my instructions."
（シノ）心を許した仲間を→
そんな姿をしたヤツを
倒せるのだろうかと。
And after that…
そして
更にバカな考えがよぎった。
If you want to know the truth,
take me down.
そんなヤツにやられるなら
本望かもしれない。
I wasn't completely sure
what you meant,
but when you came at me…
そう思いいたったとき
シンプルな答えが出た。
I reacted and…
It all worked out.
Thanks to you taking down
my clone,
ならば　本物である
俺がやられればいい。
he revealed himself.
そうすれば
お前は必ず正体を現す。
And since you read my signals,
you're the real Kiba.
それをさっきのジャンケンに託した。
ジャンケン？
So you played
a dirty little trick on me?
やっぱり　あれは　ハンドサイン。
Well then, I'll just take
on the two of you!
((なあ　これ
ジャンケンいらなくねえか？
It's useless!
That's because you are
already completely under my jutsu!
(いや　これがいちばん重要なんだ))
（キバ）そう言われて
自然と読み取っちまった。
I'm avenging the two you killed!
Hidden Jutsu! Beetle Tornado!
あのとき　お前が送ってきたのは→
俺の指示どおりにしろ。
そして　そのあとに言った言葉が。
Thank you, Shino.
((真実を知りたければ
俺を倒すんだな))
I must say though…
I had misgivings about
fighting a comrade,
何のことか
よくわかんなかったけど→
but you had no qualms
お前が攻撃してきたから
反射的に俺は　お前を。
about using your
Fang Over Fang on me.
You told me to!
結果オーライだ。
Besides, you're the one
who came at me first!
お前が俺の分身を
倒してくれたおかげで→
I didn't know which one
was the fake,
ヤツは正体を現した。
so I had to attack.
そして　サインを読み取った
お前は本物だ　キバ。
But there's no way
I would attack a girl.
Quit acting chivalrous!
そんな小細工をしてやがったのか。
なら　２人相手にするまでだ！
We brought down the fake…
but where's the real Hinata?
無駄だ。　なぜなら　すでに
お前は完全に俺の術中にいる。
お前が殺した２人の仇だ。
秘術！　蟲竜巻！
Are you all right, Hinata?!
ぐわ～っ！
Kiba… Akamaru…
Oh, Shino.
とりあえず礼は言っとくぜ　シノ。
I was the last one, huh…
それにしても　俺は仲間と戦うのを
とまどっていたのに→
お前ときたら　ウキウキと俺の分身に
牙通牙をくらわせるとは。
What happened anyway?
Nothing much.
お前が　そうしろって
言ったんだろ！
それに　お前だって
俺に攻撃してきたじゃねえかよ！
However, with this incident,
the most closely guarded secret
of the Allied Shinobi Force was
almost leaked to the enemy.
ニセモノがどちらかわからない以上
手を抜いて攻撃するとはいえ→
Most closely guarded secret?
女に襲いかかるなどできない。
ケッ！　紳士面しやがって！
しかし　ニセモノは倒したが
本物のヒナタはどこだ？
大丈夫か　ヒナタ？
キバ君　赤丸。
あっ…　シノ君。
俺は最後か。
（キバ）はぁ。
（ヒナタ）いったい何があったの？
なに　どうってことねえよ。
しかし　今回の事件で危うく
忍連合の最高機密が→
ヤツらに漏れそうになった。
なに　最高機密って？
お前が　ナルトを
好きだということだ。
えっ　どうして！？
それは　キバがお前を
からかおうとして→
うっかり口を…。
バカ！　なに言ってんだよ！
ほら　アイツら
俺たちに化けるために→
ヤマト隊長から　いろんな個人情報
聞き出してるみたいでよ！
《待てよ…　つうことは→
もしかして　ヤマト隊長だけが
知ってるあの秘密も！》
《あのときの　あんな秘密も…》
《こんな秘密も？》
ヤツらは絶対にぶっ潰す！
１匹残らず！
（３人）おお～っ！
ワン！
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華歌手
１２組の皆さんによる→